<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Uncategorized &#8211; Learn Freelancing With Fun Pro Students Assignment</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<description>Just another WordPress site</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 05:56:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8</generator>

<image>
	<url>./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/08/cropped-Grow-Out-Loud-POST-Eadaoin-and-Claire-32x32.webp</url>
	<title>Uncategorized &#8211; Learn Freelancing With Fun Pro Students Assignment</title>
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>How can you get clients through Google Search.</title>
		<link>./../../../2021/08/02/how-can-you-get-clients-through-google-search/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2021/08/02/how-can-you-get-clients-through-google-search/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[assignment]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 05:55:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=364</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[3 Simple Steps to More Traffic and Clients If you want to reach more people online, maybe you’ve done a bit of research into SEO (Search Engine Optimisation). SEO is the process of making your site more visible on Google and other search engines. The idea of being found by droves of potential clients for &#8230;<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="./../../../2021/08/02/how-can-you-get-clients-through-google-search/index.html"> <span class="screen-reader-text">How can you get clients through Google Search.</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-text-align-center has-custom-size" style="font-size:29px">3 Simple Steps to More Traffic and Clients</p>



<p></p>



<div class="wp-block-kioken-imagebox text-align-none kt-imagebox__6d8061-f7" data-tilt-max="15"><div class="overflow-hidden box-wrap"><div class="wp-block-kioken-imagebox__inner pos-abs-zeropos kt_flex_justifystart"><div class="the-content"></div></div><div class="overflow-hidden imgwrap"><img loading="lazy" width="400" height="250" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/08/How-to-learn-SEO-400x250-1.jpg" class="wp-image-114 wp-block-kioken-imagebox__img" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/08/How-to-learn-SEO-400x250-1.jpg 400w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/08/How-to-learn-SEO-400x250-1-300x188.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px" /></div></div></div>



<p>If you want to reach more people online, maybe you’ve done a bit of research into SEO (Search Engine Optimisation). SEO is the process of making your site more visible on Google and other search engines.</p>



<p>The idea of being found by droves of potential clients for free is very alluring and SEO is indeed a fantastic way to get clients. But it’s a vast and technical subject and a source of much frustration for people. To be perfectly honest, you can get quickly overwhelmed by all the articles and advice online. It’s hard to know what advice is reliable and relevant to your needs!</p>



<p>In this article, I introduce a way of getting leads and clients online with SEO without getting too bogged down.</p>



<h1>Don’t Google it! Not yet…</h1>



<p>When you want to optimise your site for search engines, the best place to start is OFFLINE!! Whaaaat? Yep, my advice is to start your SEO project with the human beings you wish to serve rather than technical tools and fiddly strategies.</p>



<h2>STEP 1: Start with humans</h2>



<ul><li>Who are your potential leads and clients?</li><li>What questions do they have?</li><li>What words do they use to search for answers to their questions?</li></ul>



<p>Ask 5 people who you could describe as your “ideal client” about how they talk about and research their problem.</p>



<p>I specify&nbsp;<em>Starting with humans</em>&nbsp;because you can easily slip down the rabbit hole of hacks, tips and strategies to “trick” Google into listing you top of the search results pages. When you start with the people you wish to serve, you’ll know the words they use when they Google their questions. Keep note of this information. You’ll need it later to create content that resonates with them.</p>



<h1>Get the SEO Explainer Series</h1>



<p>I’ve created a free, video series about SEO to help you understand the core concepts and most important tools to start working on your website’s SEO.&nbsp;By signing up, your info&#8217; will be added to my mailing list.</p>



<p>You can unsubscribe at any time. For full details please read my&nbsp;<a href="https://clairecreative.com/legal/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Privacy Policy.</a>ACCESS FREE SEO TRAINING</p>



<h1>It’s not all about knowing the latest algorithm</h1>



<p>Unless you’re becoming an SEO expert, you’re not obliged to know all the criteria and requirements for being well ranked on Google. It’s more about understanding Google’s role than trying to trick the (very smart) Google bots.</p>



<h2>STEP 2: Understand what Google is</h2>



<p>Google wants to provide the best and most relevant links for the terms searched. Best and most relevant… what does that mean really?</p>



<h3>Best?</h3>



<p>Your site should be well structured, easy to navigate and fast-loading. If your site is “good” in Google’s eyes it meets these standards. It also gives your site visitor a good experience which means they’re more likely to stick around! Win-win!</p>



<h3>Relevant?</h3>



<p>If your site is up to date with fresh content it will be seen as relevant by Google. If your site gets a lot of traffic, social shares and links from other reputable sites Google will see it as a well-respected site and is more likely to rank it higher in the search results pages.</p>



<p>How closely do the words match up? Is the vocabulary on your site matching the terms that people search? (See Step 1). When your site’s content matches what people are searching, you’ll be ranked higher because your content is relevant. This is the starting point of understanding keywords and phrases.&nbsp;<a href="https://mailchi.mp/7d20b6776c20/seo-video-series">Learn more in my free training here.</a></p>



<h1>Showing up on search results pages is half the battle</h1>



<p>When your site, or specific page of your site is ranked high on the Search Engine Results Pages (SERPs) you’re doing great! The next challenge is to get people to click through to your site.</p>



<p>STEP 3: Get the click</p>



<p>The top results on SERPs are usually ads and well known websites. If your site is listed among them your task is to get people to choose your listing and not the others. This is called “Click Through”. Showing up in the results is not going to get you any clients, but getting a higher click through rate means that your site is getting traffic and traffic means more eyeballs on your offering.</p>



<p><em>Write a good title and description</em></p>



<p>You can define how each page of your site shows up on SERPs. It’s a little copywriting exercise that can be made easier if you really understand what your potential site visitor is looking for.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image is-style-rounded"><img src="https://clairecreative.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/How-to-increase-your-cick-trough-rate-on-serps.png" alt="" class="wp-image-33488" title=""/></figure>



<p>The meta title is the bright blue text in the SERP’s listing. Use it to catch people’s attention.</p>



<p>The meta description is your opportunity to ‘tease’ the content of that page. Use this space to help the reader decide to click.</p>



<h2>Add this to your website’s pages</h2>



<p>If you’re site runs on WordPress you can use the&nbsp;<em>Yoast</em>&nbsp;plugin to take control of how your site’s pages and posts are listed.</p>



<p>If you’re using Squarespace, Wix or Weebly, each page and post has an SEO tab where you can tailor how your site appears.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2021/08/02/how-can-you-get-clients-through-google-search/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Using video to promote yourself online.</title>
		<link>./../../../2021/08/02/using-video-to-promote-yourself-online/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2021/08/02/using-video-to-promote-yourself-online/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[assignment]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 05:28:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[assignment post]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=330</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Three things I struggle with every single time. I’m sure you’ve been told how useful and valuable video can be for your business.&#160; Almost every social platform encourages you to use it by making it as easy as possible to “go live” or upload a video. YouTube is the biggest search engine on the web &#8230;<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="./../../../2021/08/02/using-video-to-promote-yourself-online/index.html"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Using video to promote yourself online.</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-text-align-left has-luminous-vivid-orange-color has-text-color">Three things I struggle with every single time.</p>



<p></p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed alignwide is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<div class="ast-oembed-container"><iframe loading="lazy" title="How to use video to promote your business" width="1200" height="675" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/k_4NNGDQ-ho?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>
</div></figure>



<p>I’m sure you’ve been told how useful and valuable video can be for your business.&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>Almost every social platform encourages you to use it by making it as easy as possible to “go live” or upload a video.</li><li>YouTube is the biggest search engine on the web after Google Search.</li><li>Viewers retain 95% of a message when they watch it in a video, compared to 10% when reading it in text!&nbsp;(Source:&nbsp;<a href="https://biteable.com/blog/video-marketing-statistics/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://biteable.com/blog/video-marketing-statistics/)</a></li></ul>



<p>Using video for your business is easier and more effective than ever. But actually making the thing, is a lot harder.</p>



<p>I started making videos for my business in 2017. I get the full-body cringe if I have to rewatch those early live streams and ‘tutorial’ posts. They were far from perfect, but even in their wonky, imperfect form, these videos helped me to get clients online. They helped people to find me, get a sense of how I work and even simply to remember my name.</p>



<p>There are a bunch of things that I struggle with, each and every time I do a video for my business. In this article, I’m sharing the top 3 (even though I could probably list about 50!!!)&nbsp;</p>



<h2>1. My appearance</h2>



<p>Maybe my hair looks weird, or I look too tired, or it’s just one of those days when I look my age +15 more years. I struggle to make a video when&nbsp;<em>…the-head-on-ya, Claire</em>&nbsp;is my first reaction to my face on the screen.&nbsp;</p>



<h3>How do I get past this?</h3>



<p>I remember – people don’t really care what I look like! I’m not an influencer. I’m not selling skincare products. Looking fancy&nbsp;is not the point of the video. The point of the video is to&nbsp;bring value to my audience. I show up on video because it helps people in my audience to understand something about their website or web strategy.</p>



<p>So here I go… eye-bags ‘n all.</p>



<h2>2. Content</h2>



<p>Is anybody going to understand what I’m trying to say? Are they even interested in this?</p>



<p>Classic impostor syndrome here. I’m always worried that my content isn’t good enough or interesting enough or that it doesn’t make sense. And there are so many resources online, why should someone listen to my take?&nbsp;</p>



<h3>How do I get past this?</h3>



<p>I remind myself of my ideal client and how she consumes content online. I remember to make a video on a topic that she has potentially ‘Googled’ recently. I break down my information in a way that looks at this topic from her specific point of view. I make videos (and blogs) that are designed to be helpful to her and suddenly, it all gets that much easier.&nbsp;</p>



<h2>3. Distribution</h2>



<p>Uch this is the worst one. I alway struggle to distribute the videos that I’ve made. My usual process looks a bit like this</p>



<ul><li>I’ll get asked a question by a client or potential client</li><li>I’ll explore the topic in greater detail and draft some notes</li><li>I’ll record a video (using Zoom) or I’ll go live on one of my social platforms.&nbsp;</li><li>I’ll upload the video to YouTube and then embed it on my website and create a blog post around it (just like this one).</li><li>Then I’ll share it on my social media channels and send it out to my mailing list.</li></ul>



<p>What I neglect to do though is to re-share it. Things move fast online, sharing the same piece of content a bunch of times is fine. It means that someone in your audience has a greater chance of seeing it. While I KNOW this, I get reluctant about re-sharing. I’m actually not sure why!</p>



<h3>How do I get past this?</h3>



<p>I remind myself… If they don’t wanna watch it, they won’t watch it, it’s fine. And if they do watch it for a second or third time, that’s actually great.</p>



<p>Another reason re-sharing is good. I sometimes get really busy and don’t have time to make something new. To keep showing up, I’ll repurpose an older piece (and silently cringe) but at least I’m showing up repeating myself, it’s better than not showing up at all.</p>



<h2>Publish over perfection.</h2>



<p>I think it’s clear from my example that you can decide for yourself what your video style is. If you can make a super-slick, super professional video every week, go for it! But it if comes down to it, just showing up with something your ideal client will get value from is enough. It doesn’t have to be perfect, it just has to be valuable and specifically for them.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2021/08/02/using-video-to-promote-yourself-online/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
